Guide to the Robert Dardano papers, 1985-2017 MS2165
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Robert Dardano papers
1985-2017
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Dardano, Robert
MS2165
4.25 Linear Feet
Collection contains minutes, correspondence, flyers, candidate questionnaires, brochures, and other material. The material dates from 1985-2017. The material was collected by Robert Dardano in the course of his membership and active participation in the Gay and Lesbian Activists Alliance and the Gertrude Stein Democratic Club. Dardano was involved with the election committees of both organizations, and the collection reflects that involvement, as well as his own personal political files. Of particular interest are questionnaires which were sent to candidates in location and national elections.
Restrictions on Access
This collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated by Robert Dardano in 2001 and added to in 2011, 2017, 2019, 2020 and 2021.
Biographical Note
Robert Dardano was active in several gay and lesbian civil rights organizations, including the Gay and Lesbian Activists Alliance, the Gertrude Stein Democratic Club, and the Domestic Partnership Coalition. He lived in Washington, D.C. and worked for the Library of Congress.
Collection Scope and Content
This collection contains minutes, correspondence, flyers, publications, posters, candidate questionnaires, brochures, and other material. The material dates from 1985-2017. The material was collected by Robert Dardano in the course of his membership and active participation in the Gay and Lesbian Activists Alliance, the Gertrude Stein Democratic Club and the Domestic Partnership Coalition. Dardano was involved with the election committees of both organizations, and the collection reflects that involvement. Of particular interest are questionnaires which were sent to candidates in location and national elections. The collection includes the questionnaires, the candidate responses, related correspondence, and materials related to the subsequent endorsement or ranking of the candidates. There are also the files related to Dardano's campaign for DC Democratic State Committee.
Collection Organization
Organized into 4 series: Gay and Lesbian Activisists Alliance, Gertrude Stein Democratic Club, Political files, and Publications and posters.
Gays; Gay rights; Elections; Lesbians -- Washington (D.C.); Gay men -- Washington (D.C.); Washington (D.C.); Dardano, Robert; Gay and Lesbian Activists Alliance (Washington, D.C.); Gertrude Stein Democratic Club; Zais, James P., 1943-1994
- Gay and Lesbian Activists Alliance, 1986-2011; Series 1; 0.75 Linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains minutes, correspondence, flyers, candidate questionnaires, brochures, and other material collected by Dardano in the course of his membership in the Gay and Lesbian Activists Alliance (GLAA). The material ranges in date from 1986-1999. The bulk of the series consists of GLAA agenda and minutes, and documents relating to Washington, D.C. City Council, Mayor, and School Board elections. These documents include questionnaires (and draft questionnaires) sent to candidates on subjects relating to gay and lesbian rights and other issues, the candidate responses, and any related correspondence. In many cases, the questionnaires are annotated with comments by GLAA members. The questionnaires were used to rank candidates for endorsement by GLAA. The series also includes flyers and mailings promoting events sponsored by GLAA and other organizations, newsletters, clippings, and other material.
  - Agenda and Minutes, 12/09/1986-12/08/1987; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Agenda and Minutes, 01/12/1988-12/18/1990; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Agenda and Minutes, 01/22/1991-06/22/1999; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Amendments to GLAA Constitution, 07/23/1991; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Financial Reports, 12/1986-06/1999; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Election Committee Minutes, 07/22/1991-08/12/1991; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Elections--1987 School Board, Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Elections--1988 City Council, Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Elections--1990, Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Elections--1991 School Board and City Council, Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Elections--1992 City Council, Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Elections--1992 School Board, Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Elections--1993 City Council Chair, Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Elections--1994 City Council, Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Elections--1994 School Board, Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Elections--1995 Special Election for Ward 8 City Council Seat, Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Elections--1996 City Council, Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Elections--1996 School Board, Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Elections--1997 City Council, Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Elections--1998 City Council, Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Elections--1998 Mayor, Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Elections--2002 City Council, Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Elections--2002 Mayor, Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Non-election GLAA work, 1986-1999; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Non-election GLAA work, undated; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Letters to GLAA Membership, 03/11/1987-04/15/1994; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Letters to Robert Dardano, 03/11/1987-04/15/1994; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - GLAA-sponsored events, 04/22/1987-04/21/1998; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Non-GLAA-sponsored evets, 03/28/1987-03/19/1995; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - GLAA website, 04/15/1996; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Clippings, 07/13/1987-11/29/1994; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - campaign posters, undated; series 1; 0.25 Linear Feet one large flat box (Flat box 3)
  - Speakers' Bureau, 1993-2005; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - News Clippings National March for Gay Rights, 1987; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - GLAA Congressional Anti-LGBT Discrimination in D.C., 2011; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Gertrude Stein Democratic Club, 1987-2010; Series 2; 0.75 Linear feet
  This series contains minutes, correspondence, flyers, candidate questionnaires, brochures, and other material collected by Dardano in the course of his membership in the Gertrude Stein Democratic Club (GSDC). The material ranges in date from 1987-2010. The bulk of the series consists of GSCD agenda and minutes, and documents relating to national and local (Washington, D.C.) elections. These documents include questionnaires sent to candidates on subjects relating to gay and lesbian rights and other issues, the candidate responses, and related correspondence and notes. The questionnaires were used to rank candidates for endorsement by GSDC. The series also includes candidate literature, flyers and mailings promoting events sponsored by GLAA and other organizations, newsletters, clippings, and other material.
  - Agenda and Minutes, 11/10/1986-12/12/1989; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Agenda and Minutes, 01/09/1989-04/20/2000; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - By-Laws and Amendments, 03/09/1987-10/16/1989; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Financial Reports, 12/1986-2000; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Meeting schedules, 1988-1994; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Agenda for 1988, 11/19/1987; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Agendas and Meeting Materials [1/3], 2002-2010; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Agendas and Meeting Materials [2/3], 2002-2010; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Agendas and Meeting Materials [3/3], 2002-2010; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Elections--Committee Minutes, Memos, Notes, 03/12/1987-07/04/1995; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Elections--Election plans, flyers, notes, 1987-1995; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Elections--Candidate Questionnaires, 1990-1998; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Elections--Delegate Training School, 1988; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - GSDC papers, Series 2 (Box 2)
  - Elections--Candidate literature, 1990 ca. --1999 ca.; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Elections--Candidate buttons, Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence--GSDC to its members, 07/13/1987-02/07/2000; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence--GSDC and others, 04/18/1988-01/07/1998; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence--Robert Dardano, 07/01/1988-11/21/1995; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Events--GSDC Annual Auction, 1990-1994; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Events--GSDC Annual Banquet, 1987-1996; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Events--GSDC-sponsored, 1987-1997; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Events--Non-GSDC-sponsored, 1987-1994; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Brochure and membership forms, Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Newsletters, 01/1993-01/1996; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Clippings, 1987-1997; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Political files, 1985-2017; Series 3; 2.25 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains correspondence, flyers, press releases, campaign materials, newspaper articles, and other material collected by Dardano. These items were filed separately from the materials of the Gertrude Stein Democratic Club, and reflect Dardano's personal political files. This series also includes Dardano's files from the Ward 6 Democrats' Club. There are also files related to Dardano's campaign for DC Democratic State Committee. As well as a small number of records for the Domestic Partnership Coalition.
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically
  - Political Files [1/2], 1985-2006; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Political Files [2/2], 1985-2006; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Domestic Partnership Coalition records, 1991; MS2165 Series 3 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Domestic Partnership Coalition expenses, 1989; MS2165 Series 3 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Domestic Partnership Coalition financial records, 1991-1993; MS2165 Series 3 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Ward 6 Democrats' Club, 1989-2006; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - DC Democratic State Committee, 1986-1991; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - DC Democratic State Committee campaign: DC Board of Election and Ethics paperwork, 1988; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - DC Democratic State Committee campaign: general volunteer info, 1988; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - DC Democratic State Committee campaign: material for campaigning door-to-door, 1988; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - DC Democratic State Committee campaign: election results, 1988; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - DC Democratic State Committee campaign: voter lists and maps [1/2], 1988; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - DC Democratic State Committee campaign: voter lists and maps [2/2], 1988; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - DC Democratic State Committee campaign: Gertrude Stein Democratic Club endorsement, 1988; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - DC Democratic State Committee campaign: financial records and fundraising info [1/2], 1988; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - DC Democratic State Committee campaign: financial records and fundraising info [2/2], 1988; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Jim Zais campaign, 1991; MS2165 Series 3 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    this file contains campaign materials including fliers, meeting minutes, election results for Jim Zais' run for DC Council in 1991 for the vacant Ward 2 seat
    Related materials
    Madeline Davis archive at SUNY Buffalo State: Finding Aid contains resources about Jim Zais.
    There are also photographs of Jim at the 1971 March on Albany for Gay Rights in the New York Public Library digital collection as part of the Diana Davies collection (the photographer who took the photos): Diana Davies photographs
  - Jim Zais memorial program, 1994; MS2165 Series 3 (Flat box 6, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Secret Service and Washington Post, circa 1992-1994; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - District of Columbia Declaration of Domestic Partnership form, Circa 1992; MS2165 Series 3 (Flat box 6, Folder 2)
  - National Equality March, 2009 October 10-11; MS2165 Series 3 (Flat box 6, Folder 3)
  - Annual wreath laying for LGBT Veterans, 2018; MS2165 Series 3 (Flat box 6, Folder 4)
  - Magnets, Undated; MS2165 Series 3 (Flat box 6, Folder 5)
    General
    4 magnets from Gay & Lesbian Liaison Unit Washington D.C. Metropolitan Police Department; Councilmember Jim Graham; Councilman Harold Brazil; The Mautner project
  - LGBT-themed Metro fare card and program Annual Wreath Laying for LGBT Veterans at Congressional Cemetery, circa 1993 and 2017; MS2165 Series 3 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Publications and posters, 2007-2015; MS2165 Series 4
  This series contains LGBT focused publications and posters. The materials date from 2007-2015.
  Arranged alphabetically by publication title with posters after the publications.
  - DC Agenda, 2009-2010; MS2156 Series 4 (Flat box 6, Folder 6)
  - Metroweekly, 2014-2015; MS2156 Series 4 (Flat box 6, Folder 7)
    Includes a special issue 20 years of Metroweekly and 40 years of Capital Pride
  - Washington Blade, 2009-2011; MS2156 Series 4 (Flat box 6, Folder 8)
    Includes 40 year history; 40 years of pride in D.C.; and Best of 10th Anniversary issues
  - Poster: Obama Pride, LGBT for Obama, Circa 2007; MS2156 Series 4 (Flat box 6, Folder 9)
  - Poster: Frank Kameny induction Labor Hall of Honor US Department of Labor, 2015 June 23; MS2156 Series 4 (Flat box 6, Folder 10)